Twenty-five years ago, scientists at CERN created the World Wide Web.
منذ 25 عامًا ، اخترع العلماء في (سيرن) شبكة الإنترنت العالمية.
Since then, the Internet has transformed the way we communicate,
و منذ ذلك الحين، غيّر اﻹنترنت طريقة تواصلنا
the way we do business, and even the way we live.
وطريقة عملنا، و حتى طريقة عيشنا.
In many ways,
بطرق مختلفة،
the ideas that gave birth to Google, Facebook, Twitter, and so many others,
فإن الأفكارالتي أنتجت غوغل، والفيسبوك والتويتر وغيرها،
have now really transformed our lives,
قامت بتغيير حياتنا الآن،
and this has brought us many real benefits such as a more connected society.
وهذا جلب معه فوائد عديدة مثل تحولنا لمجتمع مترابط.
However, there are also some downsides to this.
غير أنه توجد جوانب سلبية لهذا الموضوع.
Today, the average person has an astounding amount
اليوم الشخص العادي لديه كمية هائلة
of personal information online,
من المعلومات الشخصية على الإنترنت،
and we add to this online information every single time we post on Facebook,
كما نضيف المعلومات في كل مرة نضع شيئا على الفيسبوك،
each time we search on Google,
وكل مرة نبحث عن شيء باستخدام غوغل،
and each time we send an email.
و في كل مرة نرسل بريدا إلكترونيا.
Now, many of us probably think,
قد يعتقد العديد منا،
well, one email, there's nothing in there, right?
حسناً، لا مشكلة في بريد إلكتروني واحد صحيح؟
But if you consider a year's worth of emails,
لكن إذا اعتبرنا عاما كاملا من البريد اﻹلكتروني التي وقع إرسالها،
or maybe even a lifetime of email,
و ربما حتى عمر كامل منها،
collectively, this tells a lot.
فإن هذا يعني الكثير بشكل إجمالي.
It tells where we have been, who we have met,
فهو يحدد المكان الذي كنا فيه، ومع من تقابلنا،
and in many ways, even what we're thinking about.
وبطريقة أو أخرى يمكن أن يخبرك بالذي نفكر فيه؟
And the more scary part about this is our data now lasts forever,
و الجزء المخيف في كل هذا هو أن معلوماتنا أصبحت تبقى للأبد الآن،
so your data can and will outlive you.
بالتالي يمكن لمعلوماتك الشخصية أن تعمّر للأبد.
What has happened is that we've largely lost control over our data
ما حصل هو أننا فقدنا السيطرة على البيانات
and also our privacy.
و أيضاً خصوصيتنا.
So this year, as the web turns 25,
هذا العام، يمر على اختراع الانترنت 25 سنة.
it's very important for us to take a moment
و من المهم جداً لنا أن نقف للحظة
and think about the implications of this.
و نفكر بنتائج هذا الأمر.
We have to really think.
يجب حقاً أن نفكر.
We've lost privacy, yes,
لقد أضعنا الخصوصية، نعم،
but actually what we've also lost is the idea of privacy itself.
و لكن ما أضعناه حقاً هو فكرة الخصوصية بحد ذاتها.
If you think about it,
إذا فكرت باﻷمر،
most of us here today probably remember what life was like before the Internet,
معظمنا يتذكر كيف كانت الحياة قبل اﻹنترنت،
but today, there's a new generation
لكن اليوم هناك جيل جديد
that is being taught from a very young age to share everything online,
الذي يتم تعليمه منذ الصغر أن يضع شيئًا على اﻹنترنت،
and this is a generation that is not going to remember when data was private.
ولن يتذكر هذا الجيل متى كانت البيانات سرية.
So we keep going down this road, 20 years from now,
لو واصلنا هذا المنهج، لمدة 20 عاما من الآن،
the word 'privacy' is going to have a completely different meaning
سيصبح لكلمة "الخصوصية" معنى مختلف كليا
from what it means to you and I.
عما كان عليه بالنسبة لي ولك.
So, it's time for us to take a moment and think,
لذلك فقد حان الوقت للتوقف والتفكير للحظة.
is there anything we can do about this?
هل يوجد ما يمكن القيام به حيال هذا؟
And I believe there is.
وأنا أثق أنه يوجد ما يمكن فعله.
Let's take a look at one of the most widely used forms of communication
لنلق نظرة على نموذج يستخدم للاتصال على نحو واسع
in the world today: email.
اليوم في أنحاء العالم: وهو البريد الالكتروني.
Before the invention of email, we largely communicated using letters,
قبل اختراع الانترنت كنا نستخدم الرسائل بصورة عامة.
and the process was quite simple.
وكانت العملية بسيطة للغاية.
You would first start by writing your message on a piece of paper,
عليك أن تبدأ بكتابة رسالتك على ورقة.
then you would place it into a sealed envelope,
ثم تضعها في ظرف مختوم،
and from there, you would go ahead and send it
ومن هناك،تقوم بإرسالها
after you put a stamp and address on it.
بعد أن تقوم بوضع الطابع البريدي والعنوان.
Unfortunately, today,
لسوء الحظ، اليوم،
when we actually send an email, we're not sending a letter.
عندما نقوم بإرسال بريد إلكتروني فإننا لا نقوم بإرسال رسالة.
What you are sending, in many ways, is actually a postcard,
ما تقوم بإرساله بأشكاله المختلفة، هو بطاقة بريدية.
and it's a postcard in the sense that everybody that sees it
وهي بطاقة بريدية بمعنى أن كل واحد يمكنه رؤيتها
from the time it leaves your computer to when it gets to the recipient
من اللحظة التي تغادر فيها إلى أن تصل
can actually read the entire contents.
حيث يمكن في الواقع قراءة المحتوى.
So, the solution to this has been known for some time,
بالتالي، فإن الحل لهذا المشكل كان معروفا لبعض الوقت،
and there's many attempts to do it.
وتوجد محاولات عدّة لتنفيذ ذلك.
The most basic solution is to use encryption,
يعتبر استخدام التشفير الحل الأساسي.
and the idea is quite simple.
حيث أن فكرته بسيطة للغاية.
First, you encrypt the connection
أولا يجب تشفير الاتصال
between your computer and the email server.
بين حاسوبك وخادم البريد الالكتروني.
Then, you also encrypt the data as it sits on the server itself.
ثم تقوم بتشفير البيانات الموجودة عليه.
But there's a problem with this,
ولكن توجد مشكلة مع هذا.
and that is, the email servers also hold the encryption keys,
و هي أن خادم البريد الإلكتروني لديه مفتاح التشفير.
so now you have a really big lock with a key placed right next to it.
بالتالي يوجد قفل ضخم بجانبه المفتاح.
But not only that, any government could lawfully ask for
ولكن ليس هذا فقط، يمكن أن تطلب أي حكومة بشكل قانوني
and get the key to your data,
مفتاح التشفير وتحصل على بياناتك الخاصة.
and this is all without you being aware of it.
وكل هذا بدون علمك بذلك.
So the way we fix this problem is actually relatively easy, in principle:
و الطريقة المتبعة لحل هذا المشكل سهلة نسبيا، من حيث المبدأ:
You give everybody their own keys,
جيث تقوم بإعطاء كل واحد منهم المفتاح الخاص به.
and then you make sure the server doesn't actually have the keys.
ويجب عليك التأكد من أن الخادم لا يملك هذه المفاتيح.
This seems like common sense, right?
يبدو هذا معقولا، صحيح؟
So the question that comes up is, why hasn't this been done yet?
السؤال الذي يتبادر لنا هو لم لم يقع العمل بهذا بعد؟
Well, if we really think about it,
حسنا، إذا فكرنا في الأمر،
we see that the business model of the Internet today
نلاحظ اليوم أن نموذج العمل للإنترنت
really isn't compatible with privacy.
لا يتوافق مع الخصوصية والسرية.
Just take a look at some of the biggest names on the web,
فقط قم بإلقاء نظرة على أهم الأسماء الموجودة،
and you see that advertising plays a huge role.
وستلاحظ أن الإعلان يلعب دورا كبيرا.
In fact, this year alone, advertising is 137 billion dollars,
في الواقع في هذه السنة، بلغت قيمة الإعلانات 137 مليار دولار،
and to optimize the ads that are shown to us,
ولتحسين الإعلانات التي تظهر لنا،
companies have to know everything about us.
يجب على الشركات معرفة كل شيء عنا.
They need to know where we live,
يحتاجون معرفة مكان اقامتنا،
how old we are, what we like, what we don't like,
عمرنا، ماذا نحب و ما لا نحب.
and anything else they can get their hands on.
وأي شيء آخر يمكنهم الحصول عليه.
And if you think about it,
وإذا أمعنت النظر في هذا الموضوع،
the best way to get this information is really just to invade our privacy.
فإن الحصول على معلوماتنا هو أفضل طريقة لانتهاك خصوصيتنا .
So these companies aren't going to give us our privacy.
لذلك لن تعطينا هذه الشركات خصوصيتنا.
If we want to have privacy online,
إذا أردت الخصوصية على اﻹنترنت،
what we have to do is we've got to go out and get it ourselves.
ما يتوجب علينا فعله هو الخروج من هذا العالم.
For many years, when it came to email,
لعدة سنوات وحين يتعلق الأمر بالبريد الإلكتروني،
the only solution was something known as PGP,
فإن الحل الوحيد كان يعرف بالخصوصية الجيدة جدا "بي جي بي".
which was quite complicated and only accessible to the tech-savvy.
وهي معقدة جدا ويمكن للعباقرة فقط الوصول إليها.
Here's a diagram that basically shows
وفيما يلي رسم بياني يوضح
the process for encrypting and decrypting messages.
مراحل تشفير الرسائل وحل التشفير.
So needless to say, this is not a solution for everybody,
لا داعي لأن أخبركم أنه ليس حلا متاحا للجميع،
and this actually is part of the problem,
وهذا بحد ذاته يعتبر جزءا من المشكلة،
because if you think about communication,
لأنك حينما تفكر في الاتصال،
by definition, it involves having someone to communicate with.
حسب المعترف به، يجب أن يوجد طرف آخر لتتواصل معه.
So while PGP does a great job of what it's designed to do,
وفي حين أن "بي جي بي" يقوم بعمل جيد لما وضع من أجله
for the people out there who can't understand how to use it,
بالنسبة لأولئك الذين لا يستطيعون فهم كيفية استخدامه،
the option to communicate privately simply does not exist.
فإن خيار الخصوصية لا وجود له ببساطة .
And this is a problem that we need to solve.
وهذا مشكل يتوجب البحث عن حل له.
So if we want to have privacy online,
لذلك، إذا أردت الخصوصية على الانترنت،
the only way we can succeed is if we get the whole world on board,
فإن الطريقة الوحيدة للنجاح في ذلك هو وضع الجميع في مكان واحد.
and this is only possible if we bring down the barrier to entry.
وهذا ممكن فقط إذا أزلنا الحواجز للدخول.
I think this is actually the key challenge that lies in the tech community.
أعتقد أن هذا هو التحدي الرئيسي الذي يقع على مجتمع التكنولوجيا.
What we really have to do is work and make privacy more accessible.
ما يجب علينا فعله حقا هو العمل على جعل الخصوصية سهلة التحقيق.
So last summer, when the Edward Snowden story came out,
في الصيف الماضي حين انتشرت قصة إدوارد سنودن
several colleagues and I decided to see if we could make this happen.
قررت مع بعض الزملاء محاولة تحقيق ذلك.
At that time, we were working at the European Organization for Nuclear Research
في ذلك الوقت كنا نعمل مع المنظمة الأوربية للأبحاث النووية
at the world's largest particle collider, which collides protons, by the way.
في أكبر مسرع جسيمات في العالم. مسرع بروتونات، بالمناسبة.
We were all scientists, so we used our scientific creativity
كنا جميعا علماء لذلك استخدمنا الإبداع العلمي الموجود لدينا
and came up with a very creative name for our project:
ووضعنا اسما إبداعيا لمشروعنا هو :
ProtonMail. (Laughter)
بروتون ميل (ProtonMail). (ضحك)
Many startups these days actually begin in people's garages
تبدأ الشركات الناشئة هذه الأيام في الواقع في كراج للسيارات
or people's basements.
أو في الدور السفلي للمنازل.
We were a bit different.
نحن مختلفون قليلا.
We started out at the CERN cafeteria,
بدأنا عملنا في مقهى يدعى "سيرن"،
which actually is great, because look,
والذي كان في الواقع جيدا بسبب المنظر،
you have all the food and water you could ever want.
حيث يتوفر لك الماء والطعام في كل وقت تريد ذلك.
But even better than this is that every day
ولكن أفضل من هذا هو أنه في كل يوم
between 12 p.m. and 2 p.m., free of charge,
من الساعة 12 إلى 2 كل شيء مجاني،
the CERN cafeteria comes with several thousand scientists and engineers,
يرتاد عدة آلاف من العلماء والمهندسين الكافتيريا،
and these guys basically know the answers to everything.
أساسا، يعرف هؤلاء النخبة الأجوبة على كل شيء.
So it was in this environment that we began working.
كانت هذه البيئة التي بدأنا العمل فيها.
What we actually want to do is we want to take your email
ما نطمح إليه في الواقع هو أن جعل بريدك الإلكتروني
and turn it into something that looks more like this,
يبدو على هذا الشكل،
but more importantly, we want to do it in a way
ولكن أهم شيء هو أن نقوم بذلك بطريقة
that you can't even tell that it's happened.
تجعلك تتأكد من حدوث ذلك.
So to do this, we actually need a combination of technology
للقيام بذلك، نحتاج مزيجا من التكنولوجيا،
and also design.
وأيضا من التصميم.
So how do we go about doing something like this?
فكيف يمكنك القيام بأمر مثل هذا؟
Well, it's probably a good idea not to put the keys on the server.
حسنا، يعتبر عدم وضع المفتاح في الخادم فكرة جيدة.
So what we do is we generate encryption keys on your computer,
ما نقوم به هو وضع مفتاح التشفير في جهازك،
and we don't generate a single key, but actually a pair of keys,
ولا نقوم بإحداث مفتاح واحد بل اثنين في الواقع.
so there's an RSA private key and an RSA public key,
بالتالي يوجد مفتاح "آر سي إيه" خاص وآخر عام،
and these keys are mathematically connected.
وهذه المفاتيح مرتبطة ببعضها رياضياتيًا.
So let's have a look and see how this works
لنلق نظرة على طريقة عملها
when multiple people communicate.
حين تقوم مجموعة من الناس بالتواصل مع بعضها.
So here we have Bob and Alice, who want to communicate privately.
لدينا هنا بوب وأليس. يريدان التواصل معا بطريقة سرية.
So the key challenge is to take Bob's message
التحدي هو أن تأخذ رسالة بوب
and to get it to Alice in such a way that the server cannot read that message.
وتقوم بايصالها لأليس بطريقة لا يمكن للخادم أن يقرأها.
So what we have to do is we have to encrypt it
وبالتالي ما يتعين علينا فعله هو تشفير الرسالة
before it even leaves Bob's computer,
قبل حتى مغادرتها حاسوب بوب،
and one of the tricks is, we encrypt it using the public key from Alice.
واحدة من الحيل المستعملة، هي تشفير الرسالة باعتماد المفتاح العام الخاص بأليس.
Now this encrypted data is sent through the server to Alice,
والآن يتم إرسال هذه البيانات المشفرة لأليس من خلال الخادم،
and because the message was encrypted using Alice's public key,
ولأنه وقع تشفير البيانات باستخدام المفتاح العام الخاص بأليس،
the only key that can now decrypt it is a private key that belongs to Alice,
المفتاح الوحيد المستخدم لفك التشفير هو المفتاح الخاص،
and it turns out Alice is the only person that actually has this key.
واتضح أن أليس هي الشخص الوحيد الذي يملكه.
So we've now accomplished the objective,
مما يعني أننا بلغنا هدفنا،
which is to get the message from Bob to Alice
والذي يتمثل في ايصال الرسالة من بوب لأليس
without the server being able to read what's going on.
بدون تمكن الخادم من قراءة ما تحتويه.
Actually, what I've shown here is a highly simplified picture.
في الواقع، ما عرضته هنا هو صورة مبسطة لطريقة عمل هذه الآلية.
The reality is much more complex
إذ أنها أكثر تعقييدا في الواقع
and it requires a lot of software that looks a bit like this.
وتتطلب الكثير من البرامج بهذا الشكل.
And that's actually the key design challenge:
وفي الواقع هذا هو التحدي الذي يواجهه تصميم المفتاح:
How do we take all this complexity, all this software,
كيف نأخذ في الاعتبار كل هذا التعقيد، وكل هذه البرامج،
and implement it in a way that the user cannot see it.
وطريقة التطبيق وذلك دون أن يستطيع المستخدم رؤيتها.
I think with ProtonMail, we have gotten pretty close to doing this.
وأعتقد أننا استطعنا تقريبا القيام بذلك.
So let's see how it works in practice.
لذلك لنلق نظرة على كيفية حدوث ذلك عمليا.
Here, we've got Bob and Alice again,
لدينا هنا بوب وأليس مرة آخرى،
who also want to communicate securely.
اللذان يريدان التواصل معا بشكل آمن،
They simply create accounts on ProtonMail,
ببساطة يقومان بإنشاء حساب على ProtonMail،
which is quite simple and takes a few moments,
وهو بمنتهى البساطة ويستغرق بضع دقائق.
and all the key encryption and generation
يقع إحداث كل مفاتيح التشفير
is happening automatically in the background
بطريقة خفية وآلية
as Bob is creating his account.
أثناء إنشاء بوب لحسابه.
Once his account is created, he just clicks "compose,"
يتوجب عليه النقر على "إنشاء" ما إن يتم إنشاء الحساب،
and now he can write his email like he does today.
يمكنه كتابة بريده الإلكتروني مثلما فعل اليوم.
So he fills in his information,
يقوم بكتابة معلوماته الشخصية،
and then after that, all he has to do is click "send,"
وبعد ذلك، كل ما عليه فعله هو النقرعلى على "إرسال".
and just like that, without understanding cryptography,
وبهذه البساطة ودون أن تفهم التشفير
and without doing anything different from how he writes email today,
وبدون أن نقوم بشيء مختلف عما قام به بوب اليوم.
Bob has just sent an encrypted message.
فقد قام بوب بإرسال رسالة مشفرة.
What we have here is really just the first step,
ما لدينا الآن، ليس إلا الخطوة الأولى،
but it shows that with improving technology,
ولكن هذا يبين مع التطور التكنولوجي أن
privacy doesn't have to be difficult, it doesn't have to be disruptive.
التمتع بالخصوصية ليس صعبا ولا يتوجب أن يكون عائقا.
If we change the goal from maximizing ad revenue to protecting data,
إذ قمنا بتغيير هدفنا من زيادة الأرباح نحو حماية البيانات،
we can actually make it accessible.
يمكننا جعلها في متناول الجميع.
Now, I know a question on everybody's minds is,
الآن، عندي سؤال يتبادر إلى ذهن الجميع.
okay, protecting privacy, this is a great goal,
حسنا، حماية الخصوصية، هو الهدف الأهم.
but can you actually do this
لكن هل يمكنك القيام بهذا
without the tons of money that advertisements give you?
بدون الأموال الطائلة التي تعطيك إياها الإعلانات؟
And I think the answer is actually yes,
وأعتقد أن الإجابة هي نعم،
because today, we've reached a point
لأننا اليوم بلغنا مكانة
where people around the world really understand how important privacy is,
حيث أن الناس من أنحاء العالم يدركون حقا مدى أهمية الخصوصية،
and when you have that, anything is possible.
أو عندما يتوفر لك ذلك،حينها كل شيء يصبح ممكنا.
Earlier this year,
في بداية هذه السنة،
ProtonMail actually had so many users that we ran out of resources,
كان لدينا الكثير من المستخدمين في الواقع مما تسبب في نفاذ الموارد.
and when this happened, our community of users got together
وعندما حدث هذا، اتحد جميع المستخدمين معا
and donated half a million dollars.
وتبرعوا بنصف مليون دولار.
So this is just an example of what can happen
وهذا ليس إلا مجرد مثال لما يمكن أن يحدث
when you bring the community together towards a common goal.
عندما تجمع المجتمع معا من أجل هدف واحد.
We can also leverage the world.
يمكننا أيضا التأثير على العالم.
Right now,
حاليا،
we have a quarter of a million people that have signed up for ProtonMail,
لدينا حوالي ربع مليون شخص قام بالتسجيل في بروتون مايل،
and these people come from everywhere,
من كل أصقاع العالم،
and this really shows that privacy
وهذا يبين حقا أن الخصوصية
is not just an American or a European issue,
ليست مشكلة خاصة بأمريكا أو أوروبا،
it's a global issue that impacts all of us.
بل هي قضية عالمية تؤثر علينا جميعا.
It's something that we really have to pay attention to going forward.
وأنها شيء علينا الانتباه له لنستطيع المضي قُدما.
So what do we have to do to solve this problem?
إذن، ماذا يجب علينا فعله لحل هذه المشكلة؟
Well, first of all,
حسنا، في المقام الأول،
we need to support a different business model for the Internet,
يجب علينا دعم مختلف النماذج المتعلقة بالإنترنت،
one that does not rely entirely on advertisements
تلك التي لا تعتمد كليا على الإعلانات
for revenue and for growth.
لتكون مصدر دخل وسببا في تطورها.
We actually need to build a new Internet
نحتاج في الحقيقة لإنشاء نوع الإتنرنت جديد
where our privacy and our ability to control our data is first and foremost.
حيث تأتي الخصوصية والقدرة على السيطرة على البيانات في الطليعة.
But even more importantly,
ولكن الأهم من كل هذا،
we have to build an Internet where privacy is no longer just an option
أنه يجب علينا إنشاء شبكة تكون فيها الخصوصية ليست مجرد اختيار
but is also the default.
وإنما أمرا تلقائيا.
We have done the first step with ProtonMail,
قمنا بتنفيذ الخطوة الأولى في بروتون مايل،
but this is really just the first step in a very, very long journey.
ولكنها أول المشوار من رحلة طويلة جدا.
The good news I can share with you guys today,
الخبر الجيد الذي يمكنني مشاركته اليوم،
the exciting news, is that we're not traveling alone.
الخبر المثير هو أننا لا نقوم بهذا لوحدنا.
The movement to protect people's privacy and freedom online
تشهد الحركة حماية خصوصية الناس وحريتهم على الإنترنت
is really gaining momentum,
انتشارا وتوسعا.
and today, there are dozens of projects from all around the world
توجد اليوم العشرات من هذه المشاريع في جميع أنحاء العالم.
who are working together to improve our privacy.
و التي تسعى لتحسين الخصوصية وفرضها.
These projects protect things from our chat to voice communications,
تعمل هذه المشاريع على حماية خصوصياتنا من الدردشات وحتى الاتصالات،
also our file storage, our online search,
بالإضافة إلى الملفات المخزنة وآثار بحثنا على الشبكة،
our online browsing, and many other things.
و أيضا المواقع التي نتصفحها وغير ذلك.
And these projects are not backed by billions of dollars in advertising,
لم تتلق هذه المشاريع مليارات الدولارات كدعم من الإعلانات،
but they've found support really from the people,
بل وجدت الدعم من الناس.
from private individuals like you and I from all over the world.
من أشخاص مثلي ومثلك، من جميع أنحاء العالم.
This really matters, because ultimately,
يعتبر هذا مهما حقا، لأنه في نهاية المطاف،
privacy depends on each and every one of us,
تعتمد الخصوصية على كل واحد منا،
and we have to protect it now because our online data
ويتوجب علينا حماية ذلك الآن لأن البيانات الموجودة على الشبكة
is more than just a collection of ones and zeros.
هي أكثر من مجرد مجموعة من 0 أو 1.
It's actually a lot more than that.
إنها أهم من ذلك في الحقيقة.
It's our lives, our personal stories,
فهي حياتنا وقصصنا الشخصية،
our friends, our families,
وأصدقاؤنا وعائلاتنا،
and in many ways, also our hopes and our aspirations.
وبعدة طرق هي آمالنا وتطلعاتنا.
We need to spend time now to really protect our right
نحتاج حقا الآن لتخصيص بعض الوقت وحماية حقوقنا
to share this only with people that we want to share this with,
في تحديد ما نريد مشاركته مع الآخرين،
because without this, we simply can't have a free society.
لأنه ببساطة بدون هذا لا يمكننا أن نكون مجتمعا حرا.
So now's the time for us to collectively stand up and say,
بالتالي فإن الوقت قد حان لنقف معا جميعا ونقول،
yes, we do want to live in a world with online privacy,
نعم، نريد أن نعيش في عالم نتمتع فيه بالخصوصية على شبكة اﻹنترنت،
and yes, we can work together to turn this vision into a reality.
ونعم، يمكننا العمل معا على جعل هذا التصور حقيقة.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)